{"tossups": [{"question": "This location was first fortified by Zealous B. Tower. The<em> General MacPherson</em> was a ship dedicated to reaching this location, which Harold Stites and William Miller died defending. Miran Thompson and Sam Shockley were executed by gas chamber for their role in aiding Bernard Coy in a \u201cbattle\u201d of this location. Robert Stroud was known as the \u201cBirdman\u201d of this location, which was inhabited by men like Machine Gun Kelly, as well as Al Capone until he developed syphilis. For the point, name this federal prison located on a namesake island o\u21b5the coast of San Francisco.", "answer": "<b> Alcatraz</b> (Island and/or Prison)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of the participants in this meeting left a post-event ball early, after which the other participant ran him down to give him a portrait of himself. Before this event, one of its participants ordered his men to raise a flag, have his ships salute it, and then deny ever having anything to do with it. This meeting\u2019s most famous participant raised a toast honoring the \u201ctwo greatest men in South America,\u201d one of which was himself. The future of Peru was debated at, for the point, what 1822 conference between Jos\u00b4e de San Mart\u00b4\u0131n and Sim\u00b4on Bol\u00b4\u0131var, held in an Ecuadorian city?", "answer": "<b> Guayaquil</b> Conference (accept Conferencia de<b> Guayaquil</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Arna Bontemps\u2019 book<em> Black Thunder</em> is about this event, which was conducted by a man who had two brothers named Solomon and Martin. This event largely fell apart after Mossby Sheppard reported it to the state government. After this event, which was delayed by rain, its leader was captured near Norfolk and hanged. The state militia was ordered to quell this 1800 event by governor James Monroe. For the point, name this failed slave revolt in Richmond led by a blacksmith.", "answer": "Gabriel<b> Prosser\u2019s Rebellion</b> (or<b> Prossser\u2019s Revolt</b>, etc.; only<b> Prosser</b> is needed after\u201cslave revolt\u201d is said)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A monument commemorating this event was built in St. John\u2019s Church after a prior monument was demolished at Dalhousie Square. A surgeon named John Zephaniah Holwell wrote an account of this event, which was carried out by men led by the Siraj ud-Daulah. This event\u2019s 123 victims primarily died of heat exhaustion in Fort William, where they had been captured by the Nawab of Bengal. For the point, name this notorious 1756 event in which British soldiers were imprisoned in tightly cramped, hot conditions.", "answer": "<b> Black Hole of Calcutta</b> (prompt on descriptive answers)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man was forced to give up his rights from the Diet of Roncaglia after losing the Battle of Legnano. He elevated Austria to the rank of Duchy with the Privilegium Minus and deposed the powerful duke Henry the Lion from Saxony. This man crossed the Saleph River to participate in a conflict he organized with Philip Augustus and Richard the Lionheart. For the point, name this Holy Roman Emperor who gained his nickname from his red beard and unceremoniously drowned during the Third Crusade.", "answer": "<b> Frederick Barbarossa</b> (or<b> Frederick I</b>, Holy Roman Emperor)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "After hearing a sermon, this man once placed a bare foot on a minister\u2019s pulpit and stated \u201cHere\u2019s your primitive Christian.\u201d Vachel Lindsay wrote a poem \u201cIn Praise of\u201d this man, who was born in Leominster, Massachusetts in 1774 and is said to have worn only a co\u21b5ee sack with armholes in it. \u201cSpitters\u201d unfit for eating were produced by this man\u2019s labor. Nova, Ohio is home to the last living tree planted by, for the point, what nurseryman who provided hard cider to the early American frontier by planting hundreds of apple orchards?", "answer": "Johnny<b> Appleseed</b> (accept John<b> Chapman</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "This process was first carried out in 1974 by Frank Jobe, using the palmaris longus. Garrett Richards has avoided this process via an experimental injection of stem cells, and Masahiro Tanaka avoided it via platelet-rich plasma injections, after they each su\u21b5ered partial tears of their ulnar collateral ligaments, or UCLs. This graft process often uses a forearm tendon to replace the torn elbow ligament, and is named for a lefty who won 164 games after undergoing it. A year\u2019s recovery time is common for, for the point, what surgery undergone by countless baseball pitchers after they blow out their arm?", "answer": "<b> Tommy John</b> surgery (prompt on TJ; prompt on (elbow and/or arm) surgery; prompt on surgery for baseball pitchers/players; prompt on graft before mentioned)", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s support of the markka and native Finnish language led to his epithet of \u201cThe Good Tsar\u201din Finland. The Land and Liberty Society was formed in opposition to this ruler, who reorganized the Black Sea Fleet in response to Article 11 of the Paris Peace Treaty. Dmitry Milyutin reformed the military while serving this tsar, whose most impactful reform established the<em> zemstvo</em> system. The People\u2019s Will assassinated, for the point, what tsar of Russia who emancipated the serfs?", "answer": "<b> Alexander II</b> (or<b> Alexander Nikolaevich</b>) Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This artist created an image of a subject resting his hand on a bannister in the White House, the official presidential portrait of Theodore Roosevelt. In another work by this artist, men with their hands on each other\u2019s shoulders and bandages over their eyes walk in a line, showing the e\u21b5ects of mustard gas on soldiers during World War I. His supposedly anonymous portrait of the Parisian socialite Virginie Gautreau in a black dress was later revised to be more modest. For the point, name this painter of<em> Gassed</em> and<em> Portrait of Madame X</em>.", "answer": "John Singer<b> Sargent</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man wrote that Texas never left the Union because secession is illegal in his majority opinion in<em> Texas v. White</em>. This man ruled that privileges and immunities applied to national citizenship, not state citizenship, in the Slaughterhouse Cases. This man wrote that the Supreme Court could not issue an injunction against the President after Mississippi asked it to, aiding the beginning of Reconstruction. For the point, name this Chief Justice in the Reconstruction era who had served as Lincoln\u2019s Treasury Secretary.", "answer": "Salmon P.<b> Chase</b> (do not accept Samuel Chase)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A member of the House of Burgundy, Henry, enlarged this kingdom by merging it with the County of Coimbra. This kingdom was founded by V\u00b4\u0131mara Peres as a county of Leon. Its King Sebastian \u201cthe Desired\u201d died at the Battle of Alc\u00b4acer Quibir while fighting the Moroccans; in 1415, this country defeated the Moroccans to capture a city they no longer control, Ceuta [thay-ooh-tah]. The Treaty of Windsor allied this kingdom with England, beginning the longest currently active alliance. For the point, name this country, once ruled by the House of Aviz, that was responsible for early European exploration e\u21b5orts.", "answer": "<b> Portugal</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This innovator\u2019s mysterious disappearance aboard the<em> Dresden</em> and the later discovery of his corpse in the North Sea have led to a host of conspiracy theories about his death. This man got into a patent dispute with Herbert Ackroyd Smart after he combined direct injection and compression-ignition in his most famous invention, which Smart patented separately; that most famous innovation by this man relies on the compression of air, thus doing away with the spark plug. For the point, name this German inventor of an internal combustion engine that runs on a namesake type of fuel.", "answer": "Rudolf (Christian Karl)<b> Diesel</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Misc Science"}, {"question": "This man seized the royal Macedonian tombs after winning the Battle of the Aous River. Cleonymus defeated this man\u2019s army at the Siege of Sparta, where he died. He launched a campaign with a contingent of war elephants to protect the city of Tarentum, but after victories over the Romans at Asculum and Heraclea, he was forced to retreat from Italy. For the point, name this King of Epirus whose name now serves as an adjective for battles where the winner has taken disastrous casualties.", "answer": "<b> Pyrrhus</b> of Epirus (accept<b> Pyrrhic</b> victory, battle, etc.)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "David Brett died while visiting this landmark in 1988; police searching for his body found a small matinee jacket belonging to Azaria Chamberlain, who died in 1980, while her family camped at this landmark. The jacket\u2019s discovery prompted Lindy Chamberlain\u2019s release from prison, as it vindicated the story that Azaria had not been murdered, but rather killed by a dingo. For the point, name this landmark of the Northern Territory, a sandstone rock formation sacred to Aboriginal Australians.", "answer": "<b> Uluru</b> (or<b> Ayers Rock</b>; prompt on Australian outback before \u201crock formation\u201d is read) Page 4", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "For the point, name this state once represented by current Attorney General Je\u21b5Sessions.", "answer": "<b> Alabama</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "Petrarch described this city as a place \u201cwhere all the muck of the universe collects.\u201d A trial overseen by a resident of this city centered on Guillaume de Nogaret\u2019s conflict with the author of the bull<em> Unam</em> <em>Sanctam</em>, Boniface VIII. Six elections were held in this city\u2019s Palais des Papes during a period alternately called the \u201cBabylonian Captivity.\u201d For the point, name this French city which served as the residence of antipopes during the fourteenth-century Western Schism.", "answer": "<b> Avignon</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "When asked about the handling of this event, former UN Ambassador Andrew Young said he \u201cwas surprised and not surprised.\u201d A photo taken in the aftermath of this event shows a helicopter flying over a line of buses in front of a highway sign featuring the word \u201cMandeville.\u201d Plaquemines [plak-uh-meen] Parish su\u21b5ered extreme damage in this event, in which the 17th Street Canal levee broke. Mayor Ray Nagin controversially argued that \u201cGod wanted\u201d a \u201cchocolate\u201d New Orleans to be rebuilt after, for the point, what 2005 natural disaster?", "answer": "Hurricane<b> Katrina</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Seven councillors of this city were killed by the followers of Jan Zelivsky. This city\u2019s V\u00b4\u0131tkov Hill is the site of an equestrian statue of Jan Zizka, who defeated the Holy Roman Emperor Sigismund there in 1420. Under Charles IV, this city flourished as capital of the Holy Roman Empire. In 1618 in this city, two Imperial ambassadors were thrown out a window, beginning the Thirty Years War. For the point, name this city, the capital of both Bohemia and the modern Czech Republic.", "answer": "<b> Prague</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man once quipped \u201cFame never yet found a man who waited to be found,\u201d a quote that appears in his memoir<em> War As I Knew It</em>. This man designed a cavalry sword that transitioned American horsemen from slashing attacks to thrusting attacks. He drew the ire of his fellow officers for killing two mules after his forces captured Messina during the Allied invasion of Sicily. This commander of the American Third Army was killed in a 1945 car crash. For the point, name this American general, nicknamed \u201cBlood and Guts.\u201d", "answer": "George S.<b> Patton</b> Page 5", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "An allegorical novel by this author casts Jesus as Corporal Stefan, a French officer in World War I who refuses to order an attack and is thus executed for treason. An appendix to a novel by this author chronicles the central family\u2019s story from 1699 to 1945 and describes the life of their African-American servant Dilsey with the phrase \u201cThey endured.\u201d In the second of four sections of a book by this writer, Quentin commits suicide while at Harvard. For the point, name this author of<em> A Fable</em> who wrote about the Compson family in<em> The Sound and the Fury</em>.", "answer": "William<b> Faulkner</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "The self-governance of these people was promoted by an organization founded by Isaac Butt. Farmers from this group formed the Land League, which published the No Rent Manifesto as part of a call for agricultural reform that was passed by William Gladstone. The plight of these people led to the repeal of the Corn Laws, and the movement for their independence was known as Home Rule. For the point, name these people who established their own Free State after su\u21b5ering through a potato famine.", "answer": "<b> Irish</b> (accept word forms)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 2001, many members of the Civic United Front fled this country after a hotly contested election sparked the January 27th protests. A leader of this country consolidated his base of power by founding the CCM political party and promulgated a brand of socialism whose name translates as \u201cfamilyhood\u201dor \u201cujamaa.\u201d In 1998, this country and Kenya su\u21b5ered bombings at their U.S. embassies. Julius Nyerere [nya-ray-ray] once led, for the point, what African country that was created by the 1964 merger of the island of Zanzibar with the mainland region of Tanganyika?", "answer": "United Republic of<b> Tanzania</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "John Adams once wrote that if every man were this man, American liberty would \u201cbe safe against the Gates of Earth and Hell.\u201d In Philadelphia, this Massachusetts delegate joined George Mason in refusing to sign a Constitution that lacked a Bill of Rights. Elkanah Tisdale created a cartoon of a winged creature gripping South Essex that quickly had this governor\u2019s name attached to it. For the point, name this statesman whose awkwardly-shaped constituencies inspired the name of a form of controversial political re-districting.", "answer": "Elbridge Thomas<b> Gerry</b> (accept<b> gerrymander</b>ing and word forms)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The random assignment used in this experiment supported the idea that the behavior observed in it was situational, rather than dispositional. The book<em> The Lucifer E\u21b5ect</em> deals with some of the consequences of this experiment, and Christina Maslach called for this experiment\u2019s premature termination. For the point, name this 1971 experiment conducted by Philip Zimbardo, who assigned prisoner and guard roles to a set of undergraduates at a namesake West Coast university.", "answer": "<b> Stanford prison</b> experiment (prompt on partial answers) Page 6", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "A neighborhood within this specific locale, originally named Hallett\u2019s Cove, is home to a large Greek community and is located near the Steinway piano factory. This county\u2019s Corona Ash Dumps were turned into a park that hosted an event whose slogan was \u201cPeace Through Understanding\u201d and featured the Unisphere. Astoria is part of this county, from which Nassau broke o\u21b5in the wake of an 1898 municipal consolidation. The 1964 World\u2019s Fair took place in the Flushing Meadows Park of, for the point, what New York City borough that, like Brooklyn, is on Long Island?", "answer": "<b> Queens</b> (prompt on New York (City) before \u201ccounty\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This country\u2019s unity was strengthened by the Pact of Brunnen, which was signed after victory in the Battle of Morgarten. Charles the Bold of Burgundy was killed while fighting this country, which also defeated the Habsburgs in the Swabian War. Uri, Schwyz [shvootz], and Unterwalden formed this country\u2019s Old Confederacy after the Federal Charter of 1291. Pikemen from this nation gained fame as mercenaries and became the Pope\u2019s personal guard. For the point, name this nation, a federation of cantons like Z\u00a8urich and Bern.", "answer": "<b> Switzerland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A person with this surname was embroiled in a sex scandal after accusations surfaced that he had an a\u21b5air with Elizabeth Tilton. That man with this surname delivered the \u201cShall We Compromise\u201d speech to attack the Compromise of 1850 and raised funds to buy guns for abolitionists in Kansas, which were mockingly dubbed his \u201cbibles.\u201d A family patriarch with this surname was the first president of the Lane Theological Seminary. For the point, identify this surname of Lyman and Henry Ward, as well as the author Harriet, who later married Calvin Stowe.", "answer": "<b> Beecher</b> (accept Henry Ward<b> Beecher</b>; accept Lyman<b> Beecher</b>; accept Harriet <b>Beecher</b> Stowe) Page 8", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}